<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Local Variables: -->
<!-- file: concepts.xml -->
<!-- xml-parent-document: "manual.xml" -->
<!-- Destar Manual -->
<!-- Distributed under the same Destar license  -->
<!-- destar-version: 0.2  -->

<!--
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
"/usr/share/xml/docbook/schema/dtd/4.2/docbookx.dtd">
<book>
  <chapter>
-->

    <title>General Concepts</title>

    <para>This chapter is an overview of DeStar main components and their relations.</para>

   <sect1 id="architecture">
       <title>Architecture</title> 

	<para>
DeStar has a backend and a frontend. The backend provides the various configlets that hold configuration data. A configlet may contain a SIP phone, a Trunk line definition, one DeStar user, Asterisk options and so on. The backend contains the code that takes all of this configlets and produces the various Asterisk *.conf config files. You can even run it without the frontend (see man page for details).
	</para>
	<para>
The frontend provides a web interface. It uses Quixote and therefore it can run under Apache with CGI, FCGI, mod_python or whatever. See the Quixote documentation for more info. For small load environments and development, we use it under a standalone webserver named Medusa. The executable python script 'destar' uses this. Just start it and point your web-browser to http://127.0.0.1:8080. For more info, please refer to <xref linkend="installation"/>.
	</para>
	<para>
See the files BACKEND.txt and FRONTEND.txt on the sources for more info.
	</para>

   </sect1>


   <sect1 id="relations">
       <title>Configuration Objects and their Relations</title> 

	<para>
With DeStar you can concentrate on configuration objects (configlets) of an IP PBX. The following are the most important ones:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
	      <listitem>
	        <para>
Virtual PBX: You can have more than one PBX on your system, and their phones and applications will be contained on separated asterisk contexts.
		</para>
	      </listitem>
	      <listitem>
	        <para>
Phones: these are the final PBX extensions which have the information to configure hard-phones, soft-phones, ATAs, etc.
		</para>
	      </listitem>
	      <listitem>
	        <para>
Dialouts: you can configure specific destination patterns to be used by phones and they can be routed trough several trunks.
		</para>
	      </listitem>
	      <listitem>
	        <para>
Trunks: your system can have several trunks to make and receive calls to and from the outside world. These trunks can be shared by several Virtual PBX and Dialouts.
		</para>
	      </listitem>
	      <listitem>
	        <para>
DIDs: you can configure DIDs for your trunks and route their calls to phones, call queues or Auto-Attendant IVRs.
		</para>
	      </listitem>
	      <listitem>
	        <para>
Auto-Attendants:  these are small IVRs that act as wellcome messages for the Virtual PBXs.
		</para>
	      </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>

	<para>
The following two figures describe the relations between these components at incoming and outgoing calls.
	</para>

	<figure>
          <title>Incoming calls rationale</title>
              <graphic align="center" fileref="images/incoming-calls-rationale.png" />
        </figure>
	<figure>
          <title>Outgoing calls rationale</title>
              <graphic align="center" fileref="images/outgoing-calls-rationale.png" />
        </figure>

   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="user_types">
       <title>User Types</title> 

	<para>
DeStar has three levels of users:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
Users: they have a phone and a web interface to change some basic settings.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
Virtual PBX administrators: they can see how much people phoned on their particular Virtual PBX.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
System configurators: they define virtual PBXs, interfaces to the telephone company or VOIP-Provider, create phones, fiddle with options and create other users. They also have access to reports, call details and the operator panel.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<caution>
		<para>
If you start DeStar for the very first time and you don't have a valid destar_cfg.py file (see <xref linkend="installit"/>), there won't be any PBX configurator. This is detected by the session manager and you will be promoted to a 'virtual config user' automatically,  without a password. Then you can go to <guimenu>Configuration -> Options -> DeStar User</guimenu> and create your first configuration user. The changes will apply after saving and restarting.
		</para>
	</caution>

   </sect1>

<!--
  </chapter>
</book>
-->

<!-- End -->
