<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Local Variables: -->
<!-- file: installation.xml -->
<!-- xml-parent-document: "manual.xml" -->
<!-- Destar Manual -->
<!-- Distributed under the same Destar license  -->
<!-- destar-version: 0.2  -->

<!--
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
"/usr/share/xml/docbook/schema/dtd/4.2/docbookx.dtd">
<book>
  <chapter>
-->

    <title>Installation</title>

    <para>This chapter is a general installation guide for Destar.</para>

   <sect1 id="prerequisites">
       <title>Prerequisites</title> 

	<para>
List of needed sofware to run DeStar and recommended additional stuff to extend DeStar features.
	</para>

	<sect2 id="python">
	    <title>Python</title> 

	    <para>
Get and install Python. We use Python 2.4 for development, but maybe Python
2.3 would suffice.
	    </para>

   	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="quixote">
	    <title>Quixote</title> 

	    <para>
For Python 2.3 (see <xref linkend="python"/>) you can install Quixote version 1.0 or 1.2.  For Python 2.4 (see <xref linkend="python"/>) you should only install Quixote 1.2.
	    </para>
	    <para>
If you can't find it in your Linux distribution, then download the source from <ulink  url="http://www.mems-exchange.org/software/quixote/">the official project page</ulink>.
	    </para>

   	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="sqlite3">
	    <title>SQLite3 and pysqlite2 (optional)</title> 

	    <para>
This is only needed for the CDR (call detail record) part. Get SQLite3 from your distribution, it should be version 3.x. If you don't find it, then install it from <ulink url="http://www.sqlite.org">the project page</ulink>.
	    </para>
	    <para>
pysqlite2 is not in many distributions, but you can find it at <ulink url="http://www.pysqlite.org/">http://www.pysqlite.org</ulink>.
	    </para>
	    <para>
You will also need to build asterisk using the cdr_sqlite3_custom driver found on <ulink url="http://bugs.digium.com/view.php?id=7149">the asterisk bug tracker system</ulink>. Applying the patch could be a little annoying, but it should be incluided on asterisk source after version 1.4 is out.
	    </para>

   	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="pychart">
	    <title>Pychart (optional)</title> 

	    <para>
This is needed to generate graphical reports about the number and time of the calls made with your PBX. 
	    </para>
	    <para>
You can download it from <ulink url="http://home.gna.org/pychart/">the project page</ulink>, or get it from your distribution.
	    </para>

   	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="oppanel">
	    <title>Flash Operator Panel - FOP (optional)</title> 

	    <para>
DeStar has the ability to integrate with the FOP from Asternic in a simple way. You can download it from <ulink url="http://www.asternic.org">the project page</ulink>, or get it from your distribution.
	    </para>
	    <para>
After you have installed the panel, edit panelutils.py and Makefile on DeStar source to match the path where the panel resides.
	    </para>

   	</sect2>


   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="get_and_install">
       <title>Get and Install DeStar</title> 

	    <para>
Where to get DeStar source code or packages for specific distributions.
	    </para>

	<sect2 id="source">
	    <title>Getting the Source</title> 
		<para>
You can get the sources tarball in two formats: 
		</para>

		<itemizedlist>
		      <listitem>
				<para>
Bzip2: <ulink url="http://prdownload.berlios.de/destar/destar-0.2.tar.bz2">destar-0.2.tar.bz2</ulink>
				</para>
		      </listitem>
		      <listitem>
				<para>
Gzip: <ulink url="http://prdownload.berlios.de/destar/destar-0.2.tar.gz">destar-0.2.tar.gz</ulink>
				</para>
		      </listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>
You can also take a look at the <ulink url="https://developer.berlios.de/project/shownotes.php?release_id=10317">release notes</ulink>.
		</para>

	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="get_svn">
	    <title>Latest svn snapshot</title>

		<para>
DeStar development is done using Subversion. To get the SVN copy of the 0.2.X version:
		<screen>
			<command>
svn checkout svn://svn.berlios.de/destar/tags/0.2
			</command>
		</screen>
		</para>

		<para>
To grab the last svn copy (development version):
		<screen>
			<command>
svn checkout svn://svn.berlios.de/destar/trunk
			</command>
		</screen>
		</para>

		<para>
You can also browse the <ulink url="http://svn.berlios.de/viewcvs/destar">Subversion repository via Web</ulink>.
		</para>

	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="installit">
	    <title>Installing from sources</title> 

		<para>
From the uncompressed sources directory run:
		<screen>
			<command>
make clean install
			</command>
		</screen>
		</para>

		<para>
If this is your first time with destar, you can install the example destar config file:
		<screen>
			<command>
make install-examples
			</command>
		</screen>
		<caution>
			<para>
This command overwrites your destar_cfg.py configuration file on /etc/asterisk/.
			</para>
		</caution>
		</para>

		<para>
If you plan to use the flash operator panel (see <xref linkend="oppanel"/>) you need to do:
		<screen>
			<command>
make install-panel
			</command>
		</screen>
		<caution>
			<para>
You should add propper commands on your destar init file to start the panel service when starting destar daemon.
			</para>
		</caution>
		</para>

	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="debian">
	    <title>Debian package</title> 

		<para>
Most DeStar developers love Debian, that's why if you use Debian GNU/Linux, you should only have to run:  
		<screen>
			<command>
apt-get install destar python-pysqlite2 sqlite3 python-pychart op-panel
			</command>
		</screen>
And that's all ;)
		</para>
		<para>
You can also download the <ulink url="http://packages.debian.org/destar">Deb file</ulink> directly.
		</para>
	</sect2>

   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="first_steps">
       <title>First Steps</title> 

	    <para>
Please take a look at the man page for destar before starting:
	    <screen>
		<command>
man destar
		</command>
	    </screen>
It contains up to date information about ways to call the destar application.
	    </para>

	    <para>
If you have all the prerequisites, then start the destar script by running 'destar' as root. You should see something like:
	    <screen>
# destar
warning: Computing default hostname
info: Medusa (V1.1) started at Thu Jul 15 09:34:18 2004
Hostname: mnz66.mn-solutions.de
Port:8080
	    </screen>
  	    <caution>
		<para>
Until you have configured and applied a valid Manager API Access object (see ), you will get an <guilabel>"Asterisk is not running"</guilabel> message on some actions that require remote communication with the asterisk process, like phones state and applying changes.
		</para>
	    </caution>
Now point your web browser at <ulink url="http://127.0.0.1:8080">http://127.0.0.1:8080</ulink>. 
		</para>
   </sect1>

<!--
  </chapter>
</book>
-->

<!-- End -->
